So we've seen the basic looking at just the first
我们已经看到 只看首字母的初始版本
letter does not work very well, doesn't use enough buckets.
并不能很好的工作 没有充分利用桶
And it doesn't distribute the keys well. So now we're
并且关键词没有很好的分布 所以现在我们
going to think about how to make a better hash
将考虑如何构建一个更好的哈希函数
function. So we want the same property we had before
我们想要和之前相同的属性
in the sense that it's one function that takes two
它是一个有两个输入的函数
inputs and that two inputs are the keyword which is
这两个输入分别是 keyword ——
a string and the number of buckets, which is a number.
一个字符串 还有 buckets 的数目 —— 一个数字
Those are the two inputs and the output is the
这是两个输入 而输出是
hash value and it's in the range from zero to
哈希值 它的范围从 0 到
number of buckets minus one. And our goal is for
桶数目 - 1 我们的目标是
these numbers to well distributed, so we can have any
希望其良好的分布 所以我们可以有
number of buckets we want. The keywords will be spread
我们想要的任意桶数目 关键词会
evenly among the buckets, and every time we hash the
在桶之间均匀分布 每次我们同一个
same keyword we'll get the same bucket. So, we'll know
关键词进行哈希 我们将会得到相同的桶 这样我们将
quickly where to find it. So in order to do better
很快知道去哪里寻找它 为了做的比
than we were doing before, we're going to need to look at more
之前更好 我们需要查看更多
than just one letter of the keyword. If we look at just the
而不是只看关键词中的一个字母 如果我们只关注
first letter, we're not going to do better than having a limited number
首字母 我们将不会比之前有限数目的桶的
of buckets in a bad distribution. So, what we want to do is
坏分布做得更好 所以我们想做的是
something that's going to look at all the letters of the keyword, not
去关注关键词的所有字母
just the first letter. And based on all the letters, we'll decide their
不仅仅是首字母 我们将根据所有的字母 确定它们
appropriate bucket. We saw that with lists, if we had a list of
合适的桶 我们用列表看一下 如果我们有一列元素
items, we could use the for loop construct to go through the elements
我们可以像这样使用 for 循环结构
in the list, like this. And this will go through each
遍历其元素 这会遍历 p 中的
element in p, assigning it to the variable e and executing
每一个元素 把它赋值给变量 e
is whatever is in the block for each element of p.
对 p 的每个元素执行程序块中的代码
We can do something similar with strings, so if we have
我们可以对字符串做一些类似的事情 所以如果我们有
a string s, we can use the same construct to go
字符串 s 我们可以使用相同的结构
through the characters in s. So each time we go through
去遍历 s 中的字符 所以每次循环的执行
the loop, the value assigned to variable c will be a
都会按字符串中的字符顺序把相应的
one letter string corresponding to each character in the string in order.
单字符赋值给变量 c
So first it will have the value a, and then
所以它首先拥有值 a 然后
value b, and then value c, and then value d.
是值 b 然后是值 c 然后是 d
So this gives us a way to go through all
所以这给我们了一种方法去遍历
the elements in the string. And if you remember how we
字符串里的所有元素 并且如果你还记得我们如何把
turned single letter strings into numbers and modular arithmetic, then
单一字母映射成数字和模运算 那么
I think you know enough to define a much better hash
我认为你了解的已经足够定义一个更好的哈希函数
function. So for this quiz, your goal is to define
对于这次练习 你的任务是定义
a function hash_string that behaves like this. It takes a keyword,
一个像这样的 hash_string 函数 它用关键词
a number of buckets, and it gives it number, identifying the bucket
和桶数目作为输入 然后输出一个数字 来确认
where that keyword will belong. But instead of just using the first
关键词属于哪个桶 但是要取代只使用关键词
letter in the keyword, it's going to use all the letters. And produces
的首字母 它将使用所有字母 并且产出
as output, a single number that
一个单独的数字作为输出
represents the bucket where that keyword belongs.
代表关键词所属的桶
And your goal is to do this in a way that depends
你的目标是实现一种方式 其依赖于
on all the characters in the string, not just the first character.
字符串中的所有字母 而不仅仅是第一个
There are lots of ways to do this, so we're going to
有很多方式去实现它 所以我们将
specify exactly what you should do. So what we want to do is make
明确你到底要做什么 我们要做的是实现
the output of hash string a function of all the characters.
一个根据关键词所有字母 进行哈希处理的函数
And we can think of that with modular arithmetic, that if we
我们可以考虑用模运算 如果我们
have a circle which is the size of the number of
有一个圆代表桶的数目
buckets, so this is going to go from 0 to the buckets minus
所以它是从 0 到 桶数目 - 1
1. But what we want to do for each character, we are
但是我们想对每一个字母这样做 我们将
going to start at 0 and for each character in the string, we
从 0 开始 对于字符串的每个字母
are going to go around ord of that character, distance around the circle,
我们结合字符对应的 ord 值 沿着圆圈走一段距离
and we are going to keep going. So each character we are going to
然后我们将持续进行 所以对每个字母
go some distance around the circle, the circle can
我们将沿着圆圈前进 圆圈
be any size depending on the number of buckets and
根据桶数目 可以是任何大小
we're going to keep going around the circle using modular arithmetic
我们将沿着圆圈前进 对每个字母进行
for each letter. And as we keep going, we can
模运算 我们保持前进 我们可能
go lots and lots of times if it's a big
环绕很多很多次 如果这是一个很长的词
word. Wherever we end up is going to be the
无论我们结束在哪里 那个位置就是
bucket that we use. And let's say that's position 27,
我们要使用的桶 让我们假设那就是位置 27
who knows where it is. So that's the idea and
我们知道它在哪 所以这就是思路 然后
I'll give you a couple of examples so
我会给你一些例子
you know if you're implementing it the right way.
以便你了解 你是否是按照正确的方式实现的
Let's suppose we have as our string the single
假设我们有一个字符串
letter a, and we have 12 buckets. Well in
单字母 a 还有 12 个桶 那么
that case we're going to have 12 buckets, so
在这种情况下 我们有 12 个桶 所以
we wouldn't have 27 here. This is going to be,
我们在这里不会有 27 这将变成
11 is the last bucket, the ord value of a is 97. So for a, what we would
最后一个桶是 11 ord('a') 的值是 97 所以对于 a 我们将要
do is go around the circle eight times,
做的是 环绕这个圆圈 8 次
because 97 is 12 times 8, and one more,
因为 97 等于 12 * 8 + 1
because 97 is 12 times 8 plus 1. You don't actually have to
因为 97 等于 12 * 8 + 1 你不必真的去
go around the circle if you use the modulo that's what it will give you.
绕圈 如果你使用模运算 就会获得结果
And so the hash value for a should end up in bucket one. As another
所以 a 的哈希值在桶 1 处 来看另一个
example, if we tried hash string where the string
例子 如果我们要得到字母 b 的
is the single letter b, also with 12 buckets, well
哈希值 同样也是 12 个桶 那么
that's going to also go around the circle eight
也将要环绕圆圈 8 次
times because the ord of b is 98. But it's
因为 b 的 ord 值是 98 但是它的
going to end up in bucket two, since that's 96
哈希值在桶 2 因为 98 = 96 + 2
plus 2, which will end up in bucket two. If
所以会在桶 2 结束
we change the number of buckets, the results will be
如果我们改变桶的数目 结果会不同
different, so let's say, instead of having 12 buckets we
那么让我们假设 如果桶的数目是 13 而不是 12
have 13, and we tried hash_string on the
我们尝试调用 hash_string 函数
single letter string a, with 13 buckets. The result there should end
并传入 a 和桶数目 13 这次会在
up being 6, and the reason it's 6 is because 97
桶 6 结束 结果是 6 的原因是
is equal to 13 times 7 plus
97 = 13 * 7 + 6
6, so the size of the hash table matters, as well as the string. We don't want
所以哈希表的大小很重要 以及字符串
it to just work on single letter strings. With single
我们不想它只对单个字母有用 对于单个
letter strings, we are really getting the same thing we defined
字母我们得到了和之前定义一样的东西
before, where it gets interesting is where we have multi letter
真正有趣的是多个字母的情况
strings. So lets look at a few examples like that. So
所以让我们看一些这样的例子
where we can see the difference between what you are going to
这样你可以看到区别 在我们将要
find at hash_string and the bad_hash_string we had
看到的 hash_string 和我们之前的 bad_hash_string 之间
before is once we have longer strings. So suppose we tried
就在与一旦我们有了更长的字符串 所以假设我们
the string au, the ord of a was 97, and that,
有字符串 au a 的 ord 值是 97
when we went around the circle, ended up at location 1. The ord of u, I
我们环绕圆圈 在位置一结束 u 的 ord 值
can tell you, is 117. When we add those two, we get 214.
可以告诉你 是 117 当我们把两个值加在一起 得到 214
And modulo the number of buckets, which is 12 here, we should get 10.
然后对桶数目 12 取模后 我们得到了 10
So that string with two symbols doesn't end up in position one where the a would
所以两个字符的字符串没在 a 之前结束的
end up. It ends up in bucket ten, and
位置 1 它在桶 10 结束
as another example, we won't work through the details on
下一个例子 这次我们不会深入细节了
this one, but you'll be able to test if
但是你能够测试
your result is correct. If you try the string udacity,
你的结果是否正确 如果你尝试字符串 udacity
it should end up in the bucket sorry I
它会在什么位置结束 对不起
forgot the input size, this is very important. We need
我忘记输入长度了 这是十分重要的
two inputs to hash string, both the string and
hash_string 函数需要两个输入参数 字符串和
the number of buckets matter. So here, we're also assuming
桶数目都很重要 所以这里我们假设
12 buckets, here we'll use 12 buckets again, the result should be
有 12 个桶 这里我们将再一次用这 12 个桶 结果应该是
11. So see if you can define a function hash_string that does
11 所以看看你是否可以定义一个 hash_string 函数可以
this. And we want it to take these two inputs and produce
实现这些 我们需要两个输入参数 并输出一个
a number that tells us what bucket that keyword should be in.
代表关键词所在桶位置的数字